SALONI SINGH

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

https://portfolio-inolas.netlify.app/

SUMMARY

With an entrepreneur mindset, a dreamer and technology lover, will be helping you achieve your goals and grow. Fullstack developer with 5+ years experience in JavaScript. node.js ,express.js and other web technologies . Excellent at developing custom web applications, setting up servers and maintaining them over time. Eager to learn new technologies and apply them in world-class projects. An excellent fit for your established work process and procedures, or will readily advise and help you build proper ones.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Nationality-Indian Address- Munich

CONTACT



inolassingh@gmail.com



+49 1624537445



salonisinghfullstackengg



Inolas05

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

KNOWIS AG

April 2022- Present

Regensburg, Germany Development and maintenance of credit management solutions offered to multiple financial institutions. My role is to design and maintain the frontend template which reduces the cost, time and provides transparency to all the stakeholders.

Design Engineer

SEAGATE TECHNOLOGY

January 2016-February 2018

Bangalore, India Associated with the SSD development department. My responsibilities included : Design, development and maintenance of the web applications. Front end development with JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, Building an internal web portal for tracking and tracing different components of SSD. Modifying source code to enhance stability and to fix defects.

Full Stack Developer

FREELANCE

March 2018-March 2022

- Fin-tech Project- Company based out of the USA developing banking authentication software. My role involved building authentication and authorization mechanisms via OAuth and implementing Redis for caching to enhance performance. Tools and technologies used: Node.js, Express.js, JavaScript, MySQL, Redis, OAuth, Postman, Git (GitHub), Linux. Successfully reduced authentication response times by 40% and improved overall system reliability. Conducted thorough API testing with Postman to ensure robustness and security compliance.
- E-commerce Project- Company based out of the USA having multiple brand apparel products. My primary role was to design and develop admin dashboards using PHP Laravel to optimize inventory management. This included implementing advanced in-memory search functionality to enhance efficiency and leveraging Laravel's Eloquent ORM for data handling. Tools and technologies used: PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, MySQL, CSS3 Flexbox, Git.

Freelance

PERSONAL PROJECTS

March 2018-March 2022

- Smart-Brain: A face recognition app using an Artificial Intelligence API (https://github.com/inolas05/Smartbrain).
- Robo-Friends: A real time search app that fetches data from 2 different APIs (https://github.com/inolas05/Robofriends-App).

EDUCATION

B.Tech (Electronics & Communication Engineering) MANIPAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY July 2012-July 2016

Manipal, India

LANGUAGE

- Enalish
- German

SKILLS

- JavaScript & TypeScript
- Ajax, iquery
- React & Redux
- Responsive Design
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Redis
- Linux

- C# & .NET
- PHP & Laravel
- Node.js,Express.js
- MVC architecture
- RESTful API
- MvSQL
- MongoDB
- Postman

- GIT/Gitlab/GitHub
- Agile (Scrum)
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- **Jenkins**
- Jira
- **Unit Testing**
- Cypress